Inventory of the Joseph S. Daltry Papers, 1934-1961
Joseph S. Daltry Papers, 1934 - 1961
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Daltry, Joseph S. (Joseph Samuel), 1899-1967.
1000-107
2.5
5
Joseph S. Daltry was a music teacher and professor at Wesleyan University from 1918-1967.
Materials from Daltry's career teaching music at Wesleyan, and recordings of Simsbury Light Opera Company Performances from 1948-1950.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Received prior to 1999 (Acc. 1000-107), and received from Margery Rosenbaum in 2006 (Acc. 2006-49), and 2007 (Acc. 2007-01).
Biographical Note
Married Faith Merriman, 1926. 3 children: Alice Marshall (b.1927), Mary Augusta Merriman (b.1930), and Faith Barbara (b.1932). Married Marjorie Suzanne Rice, 1959. Died September 27, 1967.
Chronology List
October 23, 1899 Daltry was born in Heckmondwick, Yorkshire, England.
1918-1929 Organist, chorus and orchestra director, Wesleyan University
1929 Associate of the Royal College of Organists, London
1929-1931 Associate Professor of Music at Wesleyan University
1931 Received an MA from Wesleyan University. Was a member of Phi Beta Kappa.
1931-1967 Professor of Music at Wesleyan University
1933 Fellow of the American Guild of Organists
1933-1937 President of the New England College Glee Club Association
1940-1941 Lyric Opera Company
1946 Author, Basic Musicianship
1949-1950 President of the College Music Association
1953-1962 Director of the Summer School, Wesleyan University
1967 Died in Haddam, Connecticut
Collection Overview
Materials from Daltry's career teaching music at Wesleyan, and recordings of Simsbury Light Opera Company Performances from 1948-1950.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Music Dept.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Songs and music.; Daltry, Joseph S. (Joseph Samuel), 1899-1967.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Music at Wesleyan: Address Delivered at the All Wesleyan Stag Party, by Professor Joseph S. Daltry, 17 November 1934. (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan University Glee Club Series, Anthems and Part-Songs for Male Chorus, selected and arranged by Joseph S. Daltry. (3 copies)
  - Missa Salve, Victoria edited by Joseph S. Daltry. (3 copies)
  - Music Book: Serious Student
  - Music Book: Freddie Frictionless
  - Music Book: President Twirler
  - Musical Appreciation for Undergraduates by Daltry and Sternfeld, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Manual of Sight-Singing and Elementary Harmony by Joseph S. Daltry, 1935
  - Limericks (Box 3)
  - Notes for Music 1-2, First Semester 1960-1961
  - Notes for Music 1-2, Second Semester 1960-1961
  - Yeomen of the Guard: score with Daltry's notes
  - Iolanthe or The Peer and the Peri, April 8-10, 1948: master copy and listening copy on CD. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.
  - Patience or Bunthorne's Bride, April 21-23, 1949: master copy and listening copy on CD. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.
  - The Mikado or The Twon of Titipu, April 20-22, 1950: master copy and listening copy on CD. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.
  - The Yeoman of the Guard, undated: master copy and listening copy on CD. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.
  - Limericks scores (Box 4)
  - Iolanthe or The Peer and the Peri, April 8-10, 1948: original record albums with accompanying program. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.
  - Patience or Bunthorne's Bride, April 21-23, 1949: original record albums with accompanying program. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.
  - The Mikado or The Twon of Titipu, April 20-22, 1950: original record albums with accompanying program. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance. (Box 5)
  - The Yeoman of the Guard, undated: original record albums. Simsbury Light Opera Company Performance.